起死回生を図った
グー買い占め作戦
The Rock-hoarding strategy was
supposed to revive their chances.
But it was utterly defeated
by Kitami's Paper-hoarding.
しかし北見の
パー買い占めにより破綻
It will be a death match.
デスマッチだ
どっちかが完全に星を吐き出し
We play until either side
loses all his stars!
別室に行くまでやる
いいだろ 茶髪
Is that fine,
brown-haired one?
Deadly Decision
K-Kaiji!
カ カイジさん…
- Kaiji...
- Shut up.
カイジさん
黙ってろ
さあ どうする
So, what will it be?
バカ野郎が
どうするもこうするもねえ
Crazy fool!
Neither way will do.
I will quit after this game.
俺は１試合で切り上げるって
言ってんだ
There will be no such thing
as a death match!
デスマッチもクソもねえんだよ
話にもならねえ
行くぞ
待て　待ってくれ
Let's go!
Wait! Wait a minute!
分かったよ　２試合
２試合でどうだ
I get it! Two games then.
How about that?
You're hounding me.
Give me a break!
くどいんだよ　いい加減にしろ
I said one match only!
１試合だけって言ってんだろ
Fine. Fine, then.
分かった　分かったよ
１試合でいい
One match will do.
Please, just one.
頼む １試合
ったく…
Honestly, you should have said so
in the first place!
最初からそう言やいいんだよ
来い
Bring it on!
The battle of Kaiji
against Kitami begins.
カイジ対北見　開戦である
いいな？１試合だ
泣いても笑っても１試合だ
Listen, just one game.
Whether you laugh or cry,
it's just one game.
It doesn't change.
構わないな
Yeah.
Then let's begin, Kaiji.
じゃあ いくか カイジ
いちにの…
Get in position.
Kaiji?
カイジさん？
な 何だ
W-What's up?
Are you scared?!
ビビってんのか てめえ
いや…
No.
I was just thinking, it's no use
holding on to all this money.
このカネ 余らせても
しょうがないと思ったんだよ
何せ負けたら別室行き
Either way, I'll be going
to the other room.
In that case, how about betting
three stars in this one game?
なら この勝負 １試合に
星３つをかけるってのはどうだ
No way! What rubbish
were you saying?!
バカな 何めちゃくちゃ言ってんだ
そんなルール
- The rules!
- There's no problem.
問題ない　当事者が納得ずくなら
So long as the players agree,
there isn't a problem.
基本的には問題ないはずだ
ふざけろ！
You're kidding!
The proof is that this guy here
in a suit isn't stopping us!
この黒服が聞き流してるのが
いい証拠
Even so, one star is
worth five million now!
そうだとしても
今 星は１つ500万だ
Your six million isn't
even enough for two stars!
お前の600万じゃ
星２つと釣り合わねえ
Let's go.
行こうぜ
待て　早まるな
Wait!
Don't jump to conclusions!
600万は星２つの
代わりじゃねえ
The six million is not
for the two stars.
負けたら ただ黙って
そちらへ差し出すボーナスだ
It's just a bonus that
you get when I lose.
The stars are a different matter.
星は別に用意する
どういう意味だ？
What do you mean?
俺のが１つ　あと２つは…
One of mine,
and the other two...
...from these two behind me.
後ろ２人の星だ
ええっ？あの それってまさか
Excuse me, does that mean...
There is no other way left.
もう他に道はねえ
そんな… 勘弁してくださいよ
No way... Please let me off!
Please understand.
分かってくれ
And duel to the death with me.
分かって 俺と死んでくれ
な 何 言ってるんですか
いくら残り時間が少ないからって
W-What are you talking about?!
Just because there isn't time,
we needn't do this!
古畑　安藤
Furuhata, Ando!
We must take the leap now!
今 突っ走んなきゃダメなんだよ
残り30分を切る前に
Without six stars
before the last 30 minutes,
星６個くらいにしとかないと
話にならねえ
we won't have
any chance left!
今 神がかりを
作らなきゃダメなんだ
Unless we force a way out,
we're doomed!
No, no!
I don't want to!
嫌っす 嫌っす　絶対に嫌っす
カイジさんが自分の星を
どう賭けようと勝手っすけど
Kaiji, I don't care how
you use your stars!
But please don't drag us in too!
俺たちを
巻き込まないでくださいよ
俺も撤回してください　撤回
I don't agree to this either!
そうですよ 撤回しくてださいよ
お願いです カイジさん
- Me too! Withdraw!
- Just withdraw!
- Take it back!
- Withdraw, Kaiji!
What fools. And to think
I expected something else.
バカが
何を言い出すかと思ったら
あいつらの言うとおりじゃねえか
But it's just as they said.
There's no way you'd let
someone else use your last star.
最後の星 命を他人の判断で
賭けられちゃ たまらねえよ
They're a group of three formed
out of selfish reasons anyway.
奴らもどうせ
損得だけでくっついた３人
The other two would
definitely not go with this.
あの２人は絶対 首を縦に振らない
この勝負 成立しねえ
This game can't be played.
Let's go.
行こうぜ
お おう…
Y-Yeah.
Wait!
Kitami, you're running away?!
待て！北見 逃げる気か？
Hey, hey. It's because
you guys are wasting time!
おいおい　お前らが
グダグダやってんだろうが
今 まとめる
無理無理　あばよ
I'll settle this now!
It's impossible! Goodbye.
Wait!
待て
５分… せめて５分 時間をくれ
Five minutes.
Give me five minutes at least!
You're such a pest!
くどいな お前
頼む
Please!
I already said no!
ムダだって言ってんだ
まとめてみせる
- I'll settle it!
- I don't care!
知るか
分かった　カネはやる
I get it!
I'll give you the money!
そこの600万はやる
I'll give you the six million!
５分でまとまらなかったら
この600万は持ってっていい
If I can't get them to agree in
five minutes, take this six million.
So, just wait.
だから待ってくれ
Kaiji!
カイジさん
な 何 言い出すんですか
What did you say?!
What nonsense did you say?!
何 めちゃくちゃ言ってるんすか
今 600万を失って
どうするんですか
What will we do if
we lose that six million?!
目を覚ましてくださいよ
ボケども！
Wake up, please!
Fools!
目を覚ますのは てめえらだ
ええ？カイジさん…
You guys are the ones
who should wake up!
Kaiji!
俺たちは今 絶望的に
切羽つまってるんだよ
Now, we're down
to our last resort!
There's only 46 minutes left!
あと46分だぞ
でも
But we don't have to
bet everything on luck!
運否天賦に
生き死にをかけなくたって
Fools!
ボンクラ！このまま30分
経ったとしたらどうなる
What would happen if
30 minutes pass at this rate?!
There wouldn't be
any opponents left.
対戦相手すらままならねえ
Going from three to nine stars
would be a dream!
そんな状況で星３つから
９つなんて 夢のまた夢だ
運否天賦すら成り立たねえ
しかし今ならその運否天賦で
There's no such thing
as luck by then!
But now, we can at least
attempt to win by chance!
勝ちが見える地点まで
たどり着けるんだ
お前らは今 置かれてる状況が
分かってない
You guys don't understand
the situation we're in!
The flames are already
at our feet...
火の手はもう足を焼いてんだよ
この状況で
やめようかなんて発言は
Quitting in this situation
would be mere nonsense!
寝言同然　前しかねえんだ
There is no way but forward!
Running forward,
running forward...
突っ走って 突っ走って
その先にある亀裂を
...with no way but to leap
over that chasm in front!
飛び越えるしかねえんだ
カイジさん…
でも まだ他にも道は…
Kaiji!
But, there should be
some other way...
Understand your situation!
いい加減 気づけ
退路なんかもう ねえんだよ
There is nowhere left to run!
カイジさん　どうして
こうまでして勝負に…
Kaiji, why are you
so keen to duel?
To win, of course!
決まってらあ　勝つためだ
To get nine stars!
星を９個にするためだ
生き残るためだ
To survive!
For all three of us to leave
this ship with the last laugh!
俺たち３人が最後の最後に笑って
この船を降りるためだ
カイジさん…
Kaiji...
Don't cry, have courage!
泣くな　勇気を出せ
I won't ask again!
２度３度なんて言わねえ
ここ１度
Just once, just this once!
ここ１度だけ…
Have courage, to survive this!
勇気を 生き残るための勇気を
He will never get them to agree.
まとまるわけがねえ
北見さん
ああ もうすぐ５分だ
Kitami...
Yeah, five minutes
will soon be up.
We'll accept their
last remaining profits!
もらってやらあ この残りカスを
説得したぞ 北見
I've convinced them, Kitami.
What?!
何だと？お前らいいのかよ
Are you guys fine with this?!
はい　勝負します
俺もやります
Yes, I'm in!
Me too.
Kitami, the deal
for three stars is on!
北見 勝負だ　星３つ
え… いや…
No, at such short notice...
そんな急に言われても
何 言ってんだ てめえ
What are you saying?
Don't mess with me!
ふざけるなよ
You were ready to
take the cash, right?!
お前 今 カネを
持っていこうとしたじゃないか
It'd have been yours only
if this game was cancelled.
この勝負がまとまらなきゃ
持っていくつもりだった
But when it's settled,
how could you withdraw?!
なのに いざとなったら
降りるなんてあるか
Even if you lose,
you won't go to the other room!
それに てめえらは
仮に負けたとしても
You still have a safety net!
別室に落ちるわけじゃねえ
セーフティだ
臆病もいい加減にしろ！
Don't be such a chicken!
With a sum of six million
upon winning,
大体 こっちが600万
上乗せしてる分
you have more to gain than us!
勝った時の利は
お前らのほうが大きい
But you keep looking back without
even trying to understand.
なのに つかもうとしないのは
救いようもなく後向き
Those who look forward
still have opportunities,
前向きのバカなら
まだ可能性はあるが
but those who look back,
have none.
後向きならゼロ
言い切ってやらあ
Let me tell you this.
You will never have
100% success!
お前には100パーセント
成功などない
本当のことさ　臆病 臆病！
That's a fact.
You'll simply chicken out
until your brain degrades!
臆病ばっかで
脳まで退化してやがんのよ
そんなの生きてるなんて言わねえ
ただ心臓や肺が動いてるだけ
That's not called living!
It's simply functioning
by your heart and lungs.
ムダだから さっさと死ねや
悪いこと言わねえから
You're a waste of space,
so die off quick!
I wouldn't blame you
if you consider...
世間の迷惑を考えて 今すぐ死ね
船 降りたらすぐによ
...dying now and
sparing the world of trouble!
Die, as soon as
you get off the ship!
お前な…
あ　何だ？
You...!
What is it?
Are you getting mad?
少しはカリカリきたんか？
怒れ 怒れ
Go ahead and fume!
That's only normal.
それでこそ正常だ
生きてるってことだ
It's proof that you're alive!
Think hard,
now that you're here!
よく考えてみろ
ここまで来たら…
勝負だろうが
You have to play, right?
北見さん やっちゃいましょうよ
Kitami, just give it to him.
あんな奴にツキなんて
もう残っちゃいねえ
Don't let that loud-mouth
stay around anymore!
俺もそう思います
I think so too.
We can't let him off after
insulting us like that!
こうまで言われて
黙ってることないっすよ
北見さん！
Kitami!
Let's play, Kaiji.
やるか カイジ　受けてやらあ！
I accept!
結構 結構　臆病野郎も
Good.
It shows that a chicken like you
still has some guts left.
根性まではビビりくさって
なかったってわけか
カイジと北見
星３つのギャンブル ついに成立
The gamble between Kitami and
Kaiji for three stars is set.
Time is drawing close.
時 満ちる
２人 向き合う
They face off.
最初に動き出したのはカイジ
Kaiji makes the first move.
グー チョキ パーの中から
１枚を選択
He chooses one of
the Rock, Scissors...
...and Paper cards in his hand.
Seeing that,
Kitami also makes his move.
それを見て北見も動く
さっき胸ポケットにしまった
１枚のカードを取り出す
He took out the card he'd put
into his breast pocket just now.
それを待っていたかのように
背後から人
And as if waiting for that,
people appeared behind them.
They were surrounded
to be brought...
負けたら即 別室に連行するため
張り付く
...to the other room
immediately upon losing.
カ カイジさん！
K-Kaiji!
死ね 死ねばいい
Die!
You should die!
Lose.
負けろ　負けろ　負けてくれ
Lose!
Please, lose!
その声は気のせいではない
確かに聞こえるのだ
The voices weren't
from Kaiji's imagination.
They were audible.
カイジたちを
地の底に誘う亡者の声が
The voices of the lost
calling them to hell!
カ カイジさん
何だよ こいつら
K-Kaiji!
What's up with them?!
気にするな　ゴミどもだ
Ignore them.
They're just trash.
The voices belonged to those
without enough stars.
声の主は 星いたらない者たち
カイジたちが負ければ
その分 フロア内の人が減り
If Kaiji loses, there would
be fewer people on that floor.
星の入手が
いくらかとは言え容易になる
Hence, it would be easier
for them to get the stars.
彼らの望むはカイジたちの失敗
破綻　破滅
All of them
wished for Kaiji to lose.
To fail, and be ruined!
ギャラリーはこっちの味方だぜ
The gallery is on my side.
どんな気分だ？四面楚歌の中
最後の星を賭けるっていうのは
How do you feel?
To be surrounded by enemies
and betting on your last star?
関係ねえ
It doesn't matter.
Huh?
他人なんか関係ねえ
It has nothing
to do with others.
It involves me alone.
俺だ　俺なんだ
カイジさん
Kaiji...
肝心なのは いつも どんな時も
What matters is to decide
for myself at all times.
俺がやると決めてやる
ただそれだけだ
That's all!
気がついたんだ　耳を傾けるのは
他人のごたくじゃなくて
I realised not to listen to
others', but to my own voice.
俺自身の声　信じるべきは俺の力
And to have faith
in my own abilities!
｢沸騰点｣　水が水蒸気に変わる
Boiling point is when
water turns to steam.
そんな変わり目をカイジは今
身の内に感じていた
Kaiji could now feel it
within his own body.
己が存在のリアリティ
つまり｢生｣を
His own reality.
In other words, being alive.
The feeling of being alive
at this very moment...
今 確かに生きているという感触
その震えを
...trembles within him.
Check!
チェック
Set!
セット！
カイジさん！
Kaiji!
負けが込んでいる こいつに今
勝ち運があるものか
He's going to lose.
He has no winning streak now.
The flow of the game
is with me.
流れは俺　俺はこの最後の戦いに
勝ってあがる
I will win this last match
and rise up...
この余分なカードを使い切って
...by using up
this extra card.
待った！この勝負
審判！セットに入ったんだぞ
Stop the game!
Referee, the game is set!
この時点での中断なんて
認めるのか
Is withdrawal
allowed at this point?
認められない　セットに入ったら
中断は一切 認められない
No.
Once you have "Set",
no withdrawal is allowed.
そんな いいじゃないか
No way! Why not?
別に勝負をしないって
わけじゃない　ただ…
It's not as if we're ending
the game, it's just...
カードのチェンジも認めない
No changing of cards
is allowed either.
セットに入ったら
あとはただ開くだけだ
Once you have "Set",
you can only open the cards.
Kitami, you heard him!
Put it down!
北見 聞いてのとおりだ　置け！
カードを置け　置け！
Put the card down!
Put it down!
北見さん
どうしたんですか？
Kitami, what's the matter?
I don't know, but right now
I have a bad feeling.
分からねえ　分からねえが今
嫌な予感が走った
何か決定的な欠陥 ほつれ
Somehow,
there's a fatal flaw in this.
すべてがバラバラに
ほどけ散り 崩壊
I have a feeling that
everything will unravel...
...and come crashing down.
そんな予感が…
いい勘してるぜ 北見
Your intuition is sharp, Kitami.
そのとおりさ　ほつれはあった
決定的なほつれがな
That's right, there is a flaw.
A fatal flaw.
Do you remember, Kitami?
覚えてるか 北見
お前が俺たちの前に姿を現し
What you said when you
first appeared before me,
勝負を申し込んだ時に
一番最初に口にした言葉
and challenged me to a duel?
お前との戦いが最後だ
This match with you
is our last.
俺たちは勝っても負けても
２階へ上がる
Win or lose, we're rising up
to the second floor.
この発言がとんだミス
これが ほつれのその１
That statement
was a grave mistake.
That was your first flaw.
２つめのほつれは
いざ勝負をしようとした時
The second was that
when you were ready to duel,
お前が何のちゅうちょもなく
１枚のカードを手にしたことだ
you picked a card
without hesitation.
最後に使う１枚を
The decision for which card
to use at the end...
お前の判断だけで
決められるはずがない
...could not have been
your decision alone.
それができるってことは
最後に出すカードについて
So, there was an agreement
on which card to use last.
合意がなされてたってことだ
これに さっきのほつれを
つなぎ合わせると
Putting this together
with your other mistakes,
おのずと ある理が浮かび上がる
your way of reasoning
can be seen.
つまりお前らがこの最終戦で
出すであろうカードが
Also, it shows which card
you will use in this last match.
バカな！
No way!
俺には分かるのさ　俺とお前は
I know what it is.
We are birds of
the same feather,
買い占めなんて戦略を考え出した
同じ穴のムジナ
who thought of
the same strategy.
だから分かる
俺にはお前の余分なカードが
That's how I know
what your extra card is.
バカな！
どうして なぜこの男に分かる
No way! How?!
How does this guy know...
...that this is an extra card?
このカードが余分なんてことが
どうして…
How?!
K-Kaiji...
カ カイジさん 余分って一体…
What do you mean by extra?
古畑 北見にはどうしても消したい
邪魔なカードができちまったのさ
Furuhata, Kitami also has a card
which he wants to...
...get rid of,
no matter what.
そんなこと どうして
簡単さ
Why is that so?
It's simple.
仲間うちで あいこ照合するには
By using draws
to get rid of their cards,
手元のカードがすべて
偶数でないとダメ
the Rock, Scissors and Paper
cards must be in even numbers.
If not, the stars will
move among them.
そうでないと勝負の後
仲間うちで星が動いちまう
北見たちは当然 手元のカードを
偶数でそろえようとしたはず
Kitami and gang would
definitely try to maintain...
...an even number of
cards in their hands.
そこに１枚 余分なカードが
できたってわけさ
But one extra card was left.
最初の｢この戦いが最後だ｣
ってのは
When he said that this
would be the last game,
｢１回だけ戦いたい｣ってことで
it meant he only wanted one
match to get rid of that card.
１枚だけ
消したいカードがあるってこと
それに さっきの合意
And the agreement
that they have...
使う１枚のカードが
決まってたってのがその裏づけ
...also means that as long
the extra card is gone,
つまり余分な１枚がなくなれば
残りはすべて偶数
there would be an even number
of cards remaining!
あいこで残りのカードは
すべて消せる
They can then get rid of
all the cards by drawing.
そうだろ 北見
カイジさん
Isn't that right, Kitami?
Kaiji...
Hey, something
doesn't seem right.
おい 何か雲行きが怪しいぞ
あの北見って奴
追い詰められてやがる
That Kitami seems to
have been cornered.
ふざけるな！問題は
何が余分なカードかってことだろ
Don't mess with me!
The real question here
is what the extra card is!
それが言い当てられなきゃ
どんなお題目も絵に描いた餅
Unless you get that right,
whatever you said
is for bedtime stories!
It wouldn't mean a thing!
クソの役にも立ちゃしねえよ
北見 明白なんだよ
Kitami, it's clear.
バカな バカを言うな　そんなこと
Rubbish...
Don't talk rubbish!
You can't possibly...!
もちろん絶対とは言えない
Of course, I have no guarantee.
理に合わぬことが起きれば
それまでだ　しかし
If it doesn't work according
to logic, then too bad.
But if I reason it
in the usual way,
通常どおりの流れで
事が推移したと考えるなら
お前のどのカードが余分かは
もう明白
what your extra card is
would be crystal clear.
バ バカな…
N-No way...
買い占めカードではないグーと
チョキが偶数になった時点で
You probably stopped buying
when the Rocks and Scissors...
買うのをやめたはず
...you didn't need,
totalled to even numbers.
だからこの２つが
偶数である可能性はかなり高い
So, it's highly possible
that you have...
...an even number
of these cards.
そしてパーだ　お前らは
グーで勝負に走る俺たちを
Next, is Paper.
You challenged us,
who bought Rocks cards.
パーてやる気でいた　とすると
In other words...
何回パーで勝負するかは
分からない
You don't know how many times
you'd have to use Paper.
だったら無理に偶数に
そろえる意味はない　違うか？
So there is no need to
make its number even.
Am I right?
つまり 今 奇数
In conclusion, your extra card
would be...
すなわち 余ってるカードは
Paper!
Open it, Kitami!
開けろ 北見
カイジさん！
Kaiji!
残るは貴様のカードだけだ
開けろ！
What's left is just your card!
Open it!
よっしゃー！勝った！
やりましたね カイジさん！
Alright! I won!
Alright! Kaiji!
すげえ 星３つですよ
やったー！
You survived, Kaiji!
After being driven to
only three stars left...
カイジ 生き残る！残り40分で
星３つに追い詰められたが
ここでまた星３つを奪取
...in the last 40 minutes,
he won three more stars back!
再び 希望の灯ともる
Once again, there is a
ray of hope for them!
よかった
This is great!
３人てのが生きた
We survived because
there are three of us.
古畑 覚えてるか
グーの買い占めに走ってる時
Furuhata, do you remember
what you asked me...
トイレで俺にこう言ったこと
...after we bought the cards?
チョキ２枚 パー４枚ってのは
少し 心もとなくないですか
Isn't it unsafe to have
just four Scissors...
...and two Paper cards
in our deck?
買い足しておいたほうが
いいんじゃ…
Maybe we should buy more.
あれが生きた
That saved us.
あの時 俺は
｢目立つ動きはやめよう｣と言って
I told you to stop buying,
in order not to...
買い足すのをやめたけど
あれは建て前
...raise suspicion, but that
wasn't the real reason.
本当の理由は
The real reason is
the draws after we win.
勝った後の あいこ照合だ
チョキ２ パー４という
偶数の状況は
With two Scissors
and four Papers,
あいこで照合するには好都合
it is ideal to draw
as the numbers are even.
だから買い足しは
必要ないと決めた
That's why there was
no need to buy anymore.
この１件があったから
北見の最終戦の申し出に
I was reminded of this when Kitami
challenged me to a last match.
ピーンときて 奴には奇数の
カードが１種あるんじゃないかと
It led me to predict that
he might have an odd card left.
そう ひらめいたんだ
そうか…
I see!
思いがけず 俺
役に立ってたんですね
I was useful even
without knowing it then!
そうさ　こういうことが
グループの力
That's right.
This is the power of a group.
１人じゃ素通りしちまう
発想や定石を
Your team mates can point out
the things you don't realise.
仲間が確認させてくれる
古畑と安藤
Furuhata, Ando, it's because
of you guys that we won.
お前ら２人がいたから勝てたんだ
カイジさん
Kaiji!
おい待て 北見
お前 これは一体どういうことだ
Hey Kitami, wait!
What was that about?!
お前らのせいだ
You guys are to blame.
お前らが急がせなけりゃ
俺は気づいていたのに
If you guys hadn't pressured me,
I'd have predicted it.
何だと？
俺たちのせいだって言うのか
What? Are you saying
this was our fault?!
そうだ　今回の敗因はお前らだ
Yes, it's your fault
that we lost this time!
What do you mean?!
何 言ってやがる　そもそも
最終戦なんて口を滑らせたのは
You let slip that
it's our last game!
てめえだろうが！
何？
What?!
ろくすっぽ 頭も回らねえくせに
ガタガタ言ってんじゃねえ
Don't talk so much when your
brains aren't even working!
何？元々 原因は
てめえの独断だろうが
What? We lost because
you were too impulsive!
Shut up!
古畑　安藤
はい？
Furuhata, Ando.
Yes?
こうなったら
｢毒を食わらば皿までも｣か
Let us aim
for the next level.
Huh?
｢毒皿｣でいくか
どういう意味ですか それ
Let's do it all the way.
W-What do you mean by that?
パーも買い占めだ
Let's buy up Paper too!
カイジたちに足りない星は３つ
Kaiji and gang still need
three more stars.
あとのない状況は変わらない
残り時間は40分を切る
Their desperate situation
remains unchanged.
The time remaining
is 40 minutes.
They must move forward.
前へ行かなければならない
まだまだ前へ
Much further forward.
Forward, forward!
前へ 前へ！
次回　｢興亡｣
Next, Rise and Fall.